<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Cyanilux</title>
    <link>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Cyanilux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Shader Graph</title>
      <link>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/intro-to-shader-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/intro-to-shader-graph/</guid>
      <description>Hey! This post is a detailed introduction to using Shader Graph - a node based shader editor for Unity that is provided for the Scriptable Render Pipelines (SRPs), including the Universal Render Pipeline (URP) and High Definition Render Pipeline (HDRP). We&amp;rsquo;ll be going over how to use the tool and it&amp;rsquo;s features, not necessarily how to create shaders using it. I have other tutorial breakdowns that go over creating specific shader effects if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Shaders</title>
      <link>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/intro-to-shaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/intro-to-shaders/</guid>
      <description>Hello! This is a small introduction to what shaders are and how they are used when rendering graphics in Unity.
Sections :  What is a Mesh? What is a Shader? Shader Code Shader Passes Forward vs Deferred Rendering Other Types of Shaders Materials &amp;amp; Properties Setting Properties from C# Global Shader Properties Material Instances &amp;amp; Batching SRP Batcher  What is a Mesh? Before going into shaders specifically, it’s important to first have a basic understanding of what a mesh is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Depth</title>
      <link>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/depth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/depth/</guid>
      <description>Depth is a term used in computer graphics to refer to how far a fragment (a potential pixel) is from the camera. But it can be a bit complicated - as depth can come in different spaces/ranges, vary between platform, and vary between perspective and orthographic camera projections.
(Image showing &#34;Linear01&#34; Depth)  This post goes over everything about depth that I&amp;rsquo;ve come across (so you could say it&amp;rsquo;s an in-depth post about depth!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scene Color</title>
      <link>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/scene-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/scene-color/</guid>
      <description>Sorry this post is under construction.
For now, refer to https://cyangamedev.wordpress.com/2019/06/01/scene-color-depth-nodes/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertex Displacement</title>
      <link>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/vertex-displacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/vertex-displacement/</guid>
      <description>Shader Stages While fragment shaders provide colours for each fragment/pixel, we can use vertex shaders to offset the vertices of the mesh. In Shader Graph, nodes that are connected to the Master node&amp;rsquo;s Vertex ports are written to this vertex shader stage.
When attempting to connect a node between the vertex and fragment stages, they sometimes may not connect. It is usually a good idea to keep the two parts as separate as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polar Coordinates</title>
      <link>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/polar-coordinates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyanilux.com/tutorials/polar-coordinates/</guid>
      <description>When using UVs you are usually using the Cartesian coordinate system, or something similar to it at least. Pixels along the X or U axis start at 0 and increase to 1 horizontally, and the same goes for the Y or V axis but vertically. We can then offset (Add or Subtract) and scale (Multiply or Divide) these UVs to manipulate how a texture is sampled.
We can use the Polar Coordinates node to convert these Cartesian coordinates into a Polar coordinate system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
